Hey guys, welcome to another video, this is the last and final video position, basically
we are going to learn the log collectors, the log collection, so what are the logs we will
be getting collected from the Windows machine, so you people will be, if you have fresher
and cyber security, so you people will be thinking like how they are investigating the,
how they are doing the forensics and how they are investigating the machines, so we will learn
one by one, so how they are going to investigate each and everything when what happened in
federal machine, okay, so if you see a log concept basically, log is like whenever you will log
in into the machines or whenever do you some operations, even you are executing some commands
through the PowerShell, so everything will be get log, everything will be recorded and it will
be stored in one of the, one of the folders, the folder name will be, let me show that folder,
it will be under the Windows system 32, you have to search for a vulnerability and here you can
find the logs, so inside the logs you can see, there is lot of files, right, so each file will
hold saying each information, so now you can see the kernel base, it will store the kernel
based errors and all, it will be basically used for a digest, like if you want to troubleshoot
anything, you are using this logs to troubleshooting and you are using this logs to see what
happened actually in the machine, so you can see there is a PowerShell.exe, whenever any
script barracks you put in the PowerShell, this will be recorded in the PowerShell EVTX, this file
has an extension, if you check the extension of the file, it will be in the EVTX, even logs,
okay, so EVTX, even log, the extension name of an even log, so whenever you are logging into the
machine or whenever doing the logging of or any, any, any such activities, not only the login,
everything okay basically, or any progress creation or any, for this creation, any schedule task
or anything, resist remoteification, everything will be get logged inside the Windows machine,
so you can see the application logs, so the application error logs and everything will be recorded
here, okay, so not only the Windows machine, Linux machine also have a separate log for that,
to handle the error, like it will be show, what other things happening inside the machine,
okay, so this is the things we are going to use for our foreign 16 investigation,
or this is the event logs, we will be investigating when we are doing your threat analysis,
okay, so basically this will give you the evidence, you will prove what happened actually inside
the machine, okay, so let us, let us start exploring that in a practical area, so let us see,
there is a security dot EVTX, let us open the security dot EVTX, so when you double click on the
machine, it will be get loaded, okay, so here you can, so whenever you enter it to the event we
very can find the Windows logs, so now you can see the security logs, so this will give you the
evidence full logged into the machine and when logged into the machine, so there is a set of
even tidies like 464, so 464 will be like a as successful log on, so whenever you will be putting
the usernames and passwords and correct, okay, usernames and passwords, it will be get logged
into the machine, okay, so now the 464 even tidies will be logged, even tidies you see the 464
even tidies, you can see the, an account was successfully logged into the, logged into the machine,
okay, so let us stick that, let us stick that thing, let us go to the 464, so log on you can see log on
even from here, let us filter our log with the 464, so now you can find a few things like 464,
464, so now you can see the date and time for when he was logged in and when he was logged in
and all, but now you can see more information here in a general, so who logged in when logged in,
so each and everything that will be recorded right, so we will learn the windows live events in
upcoming session, but we will see the logs, we will, logs will be using for our forms basically,
okay, so we are of, so this will be used for upcoming session, so that I am covering this
in the, in this session, okay, I am covering this video in this session, okay, so basically we have
every each and every proof here, so I already noticed if you see even tidies like 464, it will be a
successful log on, and a condor surface will log in to the machine, there is a log in even tidy
called the 465, so if, so if you go for a 464, if you go for a, let me go for my approximation
and we will, I will just show you the 465 system 32, let's run the wind, windvt, logs, and scroll
down, now you can find the security dot dvt here, let's filter it with the 465, so 465 is basically,
yeah, 465 is basically a failed log in evens, okay, 465, let's filter that out, the 465, so now
465, so now you can see there is a 465, so account log down has been failed, right, so
this account name, maybe I had given the wrong username and password, so it has been failed, okay,
so apart from that we need to understand one more thing, there is a, there is a more logging
mechanism that we will call it as a systemon, so systemon provides a very good, very good overview
about the log, what happened and what was the shaft, the process executed and what was the parent
process, parent ID, parent process ID, it will give you more detail, let me try and investigate
the logs, okay, so systemon is very helpful for when you are doing such practice, like
domestic funds, domestic investigations are doing your attaining operations, okay, so it will be easy to
download and install, just download the systemon and we need to, let's, after downloading the systemon,
just go to the extract the systemon and go to the systemon folder, so the only important
information is then you are opening the command prompt, you need to run a sub, you need to run
as an administrator, so after that you have to, you have to, yeah, you have to redirect to the
systemon process, okay, systemon directory, so after redirecting to the systemon directory,
you have to be execute, you have to execute this systemon a sub to log dash i command, okay, so
it will be automatically get installed in your machine, okay, so let's see, so let's see what
other things we can do with the systemon, so let's go to the even log explorer, so after
even starting the systemon, you can find your systemon logs in the event we were just open the
event we were from here, and let's go to the windows logs, sorry, let's go to the application
service log, so you can do like this and go to the Microsoft and windows, so scroll down a bit,
you can find the systemon in s alphabet, okay, so now you can see, you know you can see there's a
lot of systemon logs, like it will be giving the process creator and process terminators or process
creation even just like one process termination even just like five, so let's install something,
let's install something, so let's install the ad is to start the exe, let me open the ad is to start
exe and okay, let's keep that, it was not running, okay, let's run the haj, yeah, let's run the haj
kk, sckk, then how the CMD has been open, go to the systemon log and just do refresh,
let's see whether our command has been logged into the, in the in the log in the systemon log,
so now now you can find the hack.exe, which we have installed it was a process creator,
process creator, process creation, even that it will be one and the explanation will be process
created, so this is the parent image, the parent will be then explorer because I have
wft installed this haj, sckk from the explorer.exe, so this is a file explorer, so the user who
executed was a user, so I am the user of the machine and the folder, that's it, I'll download
this hash of the file, let's take the hash of the file and it's too copy-casting, let's see
whether it will be working, or it will work or not, so now we can find the hash value was not matched,
where it will be, step by step detections of the antivirus programs, so it will use everything in a
detail like hash values and parent process parent image and everything, so in this course most of
the time, we are using CSPAN, so if you people need to install CSPAN, just go ahead and install
CSPAN, so just you need to download that and you have to redirect to the directory by using the
administrator command prompt, just right click on the and open the administrator and you use this
CSPAN as a tool, I develop automatically execute everything in your machine, okay,
so that's about this video and I hope you have a clear understanding about the logs operations
everything will be logged, so because in this course we are mostly when we are doing such kind of
attacks we are going to investigate this at the same time, so I am using this logs for my investigation,
so this video be very useful when you are dealing with that, yeah guys let's sub of this video and
we will continue our discussion in the next section, thank you.